So now we're going to talk about the zones, and there are three zones in handwriting.
You've got the middle zone, the upper zone, and the lower zone.
And as you can see from Lou's it looks like his upper zone is fairly pronounced here.
I would say that the upper zone is the most pronounced.
And let me show you that in a little bit more detail.
So what happens is, of the three zones, you've got your middle here, you've got your upper and you've got your lower.
So if you were to write a word such as happy, that can show you all three of your zones. H-A-P-P-Y.
So as you can see the middle zone that represents the middle of the letter, right?
The upper zone that represents these upper strokes.
The lower zone that represents the lower strokes, alright?
So what do they all mean the three zones?
Well, the middle zone, we're talking about the day to day aspects of life.
Everyday aspects of life, its social interactions.
Someone who has a middle zone that's very pronounced is someone who just gets on great with people and they're very kind of focused on the day to day activities and social interactions.
And the people who have a pronounced upper zone, that, the upper zone influences our mental thought and also our spirituality.
So there are people who are interested in thoughts, in spirituality, in mental processes, intellect, things like that.
The lower zone, that is all talking about material things.
The people who are interested in making money, eating, satisfying their material wants and needs and desires, things like that.
OK, so when you're looking at a person's handwriting, you're just having a look to see which of these zones is most pronounced, or you might find that somebody has very even distribution of zones.
Or you might find that their upper or lower zone is very pronounced.
For example, you can have someone whose upper zone is so pronounced that you've maybe got a very high loop there, and that would be someone who's very spiritual, kind of head in the clouds.
Or similarly, if you have someone with a very pronounced lower loop is someone who's very interested in their physical drives.
OK, so for our next clip we're going to talk about the form of the writing.